A Guide to the Bailey-Law Collection, 1825-1971
Special Collections, Virginia Tech
- SERIES III. NATURALISTS BIOGRAPHICAL FILES, 1825-1971
  - Subseries A. Numerical Files, 1825-1970
    - #534-550 (Box 17, Folder 9)
      - #539 - Hales, B. J., 1928-1945
      - #540 - Hastings, Walter E., 1926
      - #541 - Johnson, E. E., 1926-1944
      - #542 - Jennings, Richard D., 1938-1952
      - #543 - Surber, Eugene W., 1952
      - #544 - Truesdale, Fred K., 1944-1956, n.d.
      - #545 - Wade, James S., 1944-1961
      - #546 - VanTyre, J., 1931-1951
      - #547 - Underdown, Henry T., 1949-1953
      - #548 - Pangburn, C. H., 1929
      - #549 - Jacot, Edouard, 1945
      - #550 - Hargrave, Lyndon L., 1945-19
    - #551-559 (Box 17, Folder 10)
      - #551 - Brown, Wilmot W., 1938-1953
      - #552 - Hutcheson, Scott, 1942
      - #553 - Enders, Howard E., 1951
      - #554 - Lyle, Robert B., 1932
      - #555 - Webber, E. Leland, 1960
      - #556 - Schwartz, Albert, 1949
      - #557 - Court, Edward J., 1935-1962
      - #558 - Bond, James, 1952
      - #559 - Cruttenden, John R., 1941-1944
    - #560-567 (Box 17, Folder 11)
      - #560 - Walkinshaw, Lawrence H., 1942
      - #561 - Anderson, R. M., 1945-1946
      - #562 - Lowery, George H., 1941-1950
      - #563 - Miller, E. Morton, 1951-1953
      - #564 - Sanborn, Colin C., 1952
      - #565 - Jaques, Francis Lee, 1952
      - #566 - Gilliard, E. Thomas, 1953
      - #567 - Simson-Spicer, Theodore, 1936-1967
    - #568-576 (Box 17, Folder 12)
      - #568 - Darden, C. S., n.d.
      - #569 - Chapin, James, 1952-1964
      - #570 - Pough, Rich. H., 1948-1962
      - #571 - Lewis, Ivy, 1951-1964, n.d.
      - #572 - Biglow, Fred H., 1942-1948, n.d.
      - #573 - Schwartz, Ernest, 1941-1951
      - #574 - Phillips, Allan, 1955-1966
      - #575 - Monroe, Bert L., 1941-1960
      - #576 - Orr, Robert T., 1940-1955
    - #577-586 (Box 17, Folder 13)
      - #577 - Eckelberry, Don R., 1952
      - #578 - Lincoln, Frederick C., 1930-1948, n.d.
      - #579 - Smith, Maxwell, 1948
      - #580 - Wilk, Bert, 1949-1958
      - #581 - Moreno, Abelardo, 1949-1950
      - #582 - Grimes, Samuel A., 1951
      - #583 - Bowdish, B. S., 1948-1949, n.d.
      - #584 - Rett, Egmont Z., 1961
      - #585 - Unglish, Will E., 1939-1961, n.d.
      - #586 - Beard, Daniel C., 1924
    - #587 - Miller, Loye and Alden H., 1941-1970, n.d., [2 folders] (Box 18, Folder 1)
    - #588-596 (Box 18, Folder 2)
      - #588 - Stillwell, Jerry E., 1953
      - #589 - Hill, Frederick F., 1937
      - #590 - Huey, Lawrence M., 1950-1961, n.d.
      - #591 - Shufeldt, R. W., 1915, n.d.
      - #592 - Mann, W. M., 1955-1960
      - #593 - Griffith, Ernest S., 1949-1955
      - #594 - Geist, Otto W., 1942
      - #595 - Stevens, Lawrence T., 1954-1955
      - #596 - Dixon, J. B., 1953-1962, n.d.
    - #597-607 (Box 18, Folder 3)
      - #597 - Albright, Ray, 1954
      - #598 - Roberts, Bert, 1952-1953
      - #599 - Bailey, John Wendell, 1954-1956
      - #600 - Edge, C. N. (Mrs.), 1952-1962
      - #601 - Miller, Lyle D., 1948-1965, n.d.
      - #602 - Parkes, Kenneth C., 1951
      - #603 - Davis, William B., 1948-1952
      - #604 - Hanson, Herbert C., 1952
      - #605 - Virginia Society of Ornithology, 1952-1953
      - #606 - Burt, William H., 1952
      - #607 - Stevenson, Henry M., 1945
    - #608-615 (Box 18, Folder 4)
      - #608 - Jones, E. T., 1948-1952
      - #609 - Bailey, Harold H. and Laura B., 1915-1968, n.d.
      - #610 - Osgood, F. L., 1939-1953
      - #611 - Todd, H. O., 1937
      - #612 - Cassel, Joseph F., 1941
      - #613 - [empty]
      - #614 - Zimmer, John T., 1941-1952
      - #615 - Martin del Campo, Rafael, 1944-1945
    - #616-624 (Box 18, Folder 5)
      - #616 - Ross, Allan, 1952
      - #617 - Favour, Paul G., 1953
      - #618 - Sechrist, E. E., 1949
      - #619 - Mulholland, J. W., 1939
      - #620 - Beatty, Harry A., 1939-1957
      - #621 - Hoover, Herbert, 1937-1964, n.d.
      - #622 - Harris, William G., 1951-1958
      - #623 - Shannon, Waylan, 1949
      - #624 - Daynes, Donald J., 1940
    - #625-636 (Box 18, Folder 6)
      - #625 - Stewart, Ronald M., 1944-1948
      - #626 - Preston, Frank W., 1961
      - #627 - Dalquest, Walter, 1939, n.d.
      - #628 - Goodpaster, Woodrow, 1941
      - #629 - Cowan, I. McT., 1957
      - #630 - Reynolds, Bruce D., 1955-1957
      - #631 - Fuller, Arthur B., 1958-1960
      - #632 - Nice, Margaret M., 1931
      - #633 - Wilson, Harold C., 1957-1958
      - #634 - Duvall, Allen J., 1957
      - #635 - Michener, Harold, 1949, n.d.
      - #636 - Torre y Huerta, Carlos de la, 1956-1957, n.d.
    - #637-638 (Box 18, Folder 7)
      - #637 - Cabell, James Branch, 1945-1949, n.d.
      - #638 - Law, J. Eugene, 1900-1933
    - #639-662 (Box 18, Folder 8)
      - #639 - Morcum, G. Frean, 1919
      - #640 - de Boe, Michael Price, 1953-1956
      - #641 - Benchley, Mrs. Belle, 1953
      - #642 - Eisenmann, Eugene, 1952
      - #643 - Grenfell, Sir wilfrid, n.d.
      - #644 - Howell, Thomas R., 1957
      - #645 - Hamilton, Holt, 1941
      - #646 - Howard, Hildegarde, 1958
      - #647 - Jonas, John, 1938
      - #648 - Krider, John, 1870
      - #649 - Morton, J. L., 1944
      - #650 - Stanley, Jim, 1946
      - #651 - Sanger, William T., 1956
      - #652 - Stager, Kenneth E., 1958
      - #653 - Sobrinho, Jos Castano, 1922
      - #654 - Schwartz, Frank, 1942
      - #655 - Villalba, Gaston s., 1935-1953
      - #656 - Schmidt, Karl P., 1937
      - #657 - McCabe, Thomas T., 1931-1961
      - #658 - Owen, Plass, 1961-1962
      - #659 - Hoy, Nelson D., 1961
      - #660 - Hahn, Paul, 1961-1962, n.d.
      - #661 - Oehser, Paul H., 1961
      - #662 - English, Almon O., 1964, n.d.
    - "Index of Autograph Naturalist Letters", n.d. (Box 18, Folder 9)
    - "Index, Autograph Letters of Naturalists", n.d. (Box 18, Folder 10-11)
  - Subseries B. Alphabetical Files, 1836-1971
    - Aa-Am (Box 18, Folder 12)
      - Abbott, Clinton G., 1942
      - Abbott, Gerard Alan, n.d.
      - Alexander, Annie Montague, 1958
      - Allen, A. A., 1934
      - Amedeo, Luigi, 1910
    - An-Bah (Box 18, Folder 13)
      - Anderson, E. M., 1913
      - Anderson, R. M., n.d.
      - Andrews, Lee, n.d.
      - Atkinson, Alfred, 1945
      - Atkinson, George F., 1887
      - Atkinson, Spencer, n.d.
      - Audubon, John James, 1937, n.d.
    - Bailey, Alfred M., 1947, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 1)
    - Bailey, Harold Balch - papers, 1836-1929, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 2)
      [includes material relating to 19th-century Massachusetts militia units, one item bearing the signature of John Quincy Adams]
    - Bailey, Harold Balch - autograph book, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 3)
      Contains signatures of:
      Ulysses S. Grant [Union Army general and United States president]
      Ambrose E. Burnside [Union Army general]
      William Tecumseh Sherman [Union Army general]
      Philip H. Sheridan [Union Army general]
      J. Tyler
      J. Davis
      Henry P. Baldwin [Michigan governor]
      Levi P. Morton [United States vice-president]
      Hannibal Hamlin [United States vice-president]
      William Claflin [Massachusetts governor]
      Douglas Sladen [English author]
      [S. W. Lincoln Jr.?]
      Grover Cleveland [United States president]
      Frances Folsom Cleveland [United States first lady]
      Rutherford B. Hayes [United States president]
      John J. Audubon [naturalist]
      Joshua L. Chamberlain [Maine governor]
      Benjamin F. Butler [Union Army general]
      Geo. H. Hepworth [minister and journalist]
      Walter Harriman [New Hampshire governor]
      Horace Greeley [newspaper editor; 1872 presidential candidate]
      Joseph [W.?] Donahue
      James M. Harvey [Kansas governor]
      John W. Geary [Pennsylvania governor]
      John Hoffman [New York governor]
      Hans von Bulow [pianist]
      Lucius Fairchild [Wisconsin governor]
      Robert W. Chambers [American author]
      Henry Huntly Haight [California governor]
      Geo. S. Boutwell [United States secretary of the treasury]
      Henry L. Pierce [Massachusetts congressman]
      Charles [illegible]
      E. M. Pease [Texas governor]
      H. L. Dawes [Massachusetts senator]
      William Gaston [Massachusetts governor]
      Alexander H. Rice [Massachusetts governor]
      Henry W. Longfellow [poet]
      William Dean Howells [author][with poem]
      Margaret J. Preston [poet]
      Oliver Wendall Holmes [United States Supreme Court justice][with poem]
      William Cullen Bryant [poet and newspaper editor]
      Nathaniel B. Shurtleff [Boston mayor]
      Aaron V. Brown [United States postmaster-general]
      Marshall Jewell [United States postmaster-general]
      Morrison Remick Waite [United States Supreme Court chief justice]
      William Worth Belknap [United States secretary of war]
      Asa Gray [Harvard University professor of botany]
      Olive Thorne Miller [naturalist and children's writer]
      James Parton [author/biographer]
      Bayard Taylor [poet]
      Thomas Hughes [English author]
      [illegible]
      Frank Stockton [author]
      William R. Marshall [Minnesota governor]
      W. L. Champney [artist][with drawing]
      P. A. Rearick [United States Navy captain]
    - Bailey, Harold H., 1913-1935, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 4)
    - Bailey, Laura Beatty Law, 1948-1968, [3 folders] (Box 19, Folder 5)
    - Baj-Bl (Box 19, Folder 6)
      - Baker, Jack D., 1924
      - Barlow, G. R., 1911
      - Barrows, Walter B., 1921-1923
      - Bartsch, Paul, 1941-1946
      - Batchelder, Charles F., 1952
      - Baynard, Oscar E., n.d.
      - Beal, F. E. L., 1916
      - Beard, Daniel B. Jr., 1950-1953
      - Benchley, Belle J., 1947
      - Benedict, James E., 1931
      - Benners, G. B., 1913
      - Bent, A. C., 1936-1944, n.d.
      - Blunt, William, 1909
    - Bm-Bres (Box 19, Folder 7)
      - Boardman, George A., 1878-1904, n.d.
      - Boughton, Donald C., 1936
      - Boulenger, George Albert, 1906
      - Bowdish, Beecher S., 1917
      - Bowles, J. H., 1913-1930, n.d.
      - Bradbury, William C., n.d.
      - Bragg, Laura, 1914
      - [Brandt], Herb, 1947
      - Breninger, George F., 1905
    - Bret (Box 19, Folder 8)
      - Bretherton, Bernard J., n.d.
        [notebook containing color plates extracted from unidentified publication]
    - Breu-Bro (Box 20, Folder 1)
      - Brewster, William, 1913-1920
      - Brimley, H. H., 1927
      - Britten, G. S., 1930
      - Brock, Elizabeth C., 1920
      - Brooks, Allan, 1918-1921, n.d., [see also Oversize Materials]
        [includes original artwork]
      - Brooks, Earle A., 1913
    - Brp-Brz (Box 20, Folder 2)
      - Bryant, Walter E., 1880-1905, n.d.
    - Bs-Bz (Box 20, Folder 3)
      - Burleigh, Thomas D., 1936, n.d.
      - Burtch, Verdi, 1909-1920
    - C (Box 20, Folder 4)
      - Chamberlain, James L., 1962
      - Chambers, W. Lee, 1913-1917, n.d.
      - Chapman, Frank M., 1913-1925
      - Cherrie, George K., 1947
      - Chisholm, D., 1928
      - Cleaves, Howard, 1917-1928, n.d.
      - Cole, L. J., 1935
      - Cook, C. C., n.d.
      - Cookman, Alfred, 1914, n.d.
      - Cooper, James G., 1887
      - Cordier, A. H., 1923
      - Core, Earl L., 1962
      - Craven, Jesse T., 1910, n.d.
      - Crispin, William B., n.d.
      - Curl, L. F., 1953
    - Da-Dh (Box 20, Folder 5)
      - Davis, W. B., 1952
      - Dawson, W. Leon, 1913
      - Daynes, Donald J., [1931?]
      - de Boe, Michael Price, 1934
      - Denmead, Talbott, 1936
    - Dia-Dil (Box 20, Folder 6)
      - Dille, F. M., 1883-1948
    - Dim-Diz (Box 20, Folder 7)
      - Dixon, James B., 1935-1966, n.d.
      - Dixon, Joseph, 1917
    - Dj-Dz (Box 20, Folder 8)
      - Doutt, J. Kenneth, 1946-1947
      - Duprey, H. F., n.d.
      - Duvall, Allen, 1954
      - Dyche, Lewis Lindsay, n.d.
    - Ea-Em (Box 20, Folder 9)
      - Edge, Rosalie (Mrs. C. N.), 1934-1953
      - Edwards, H. Arden, 1916-1917, n.d.
      - Edwards, Ernest, 1955
      - Emerson, W. Otto, 1887-1932, n.d.
    - En-Fn (Box 20, Folder 10)
      - Ennis, J. Harold, 1913-1947
      - Evans, J. Harold, 1913
      - Eyerdam, Walter J., 1938-1959
      - Fairchild, Herman LeRoy, 1932-[1959], n.d.
      - Farley, Frank L., 1935, n.d.
      - Ferneyhough, J. Bowie, n.d.
      - Figgins, J. D., 1920-1935
      - Fisher, A. K., 1913-1946
      - Fisher, Walter K., 1906-1911
      - Fleming, J. H., 1917
    - Ford, E. R.
      - Field notes (Illinois), 1888-1912, [2 folders] (Box 20, Folder 11)
      - Bird observations (Newaygo County, Michigan), 1922-1929 (Box 20, Folder 12)
      - Bird observations (Newaygo County, Michigan), 1943-1947 (Box 20, Folder 13)
      - Nest and egg logbook (Illinois, Michigan, Minnesota and Wisconsin), 1889-1948, [2 folders] (Box 21, Folder 1)
    - Fp-Fz (Box 21, Folder 2)
      - Fuertes, Louis Agassiz, 1901-1924, n.d.
    - G (Box 21, Folder 3)
      - Galvin, John, 1901
      - Gatling, George B., 1944
      - Gentry, Thomas G., 1877
      - Giles, Roscoe I., 1913, n.d.
      - Goethe, C. M., 1956-1959, n.d.
      - Gosse, Philip H., n.d.
      - Gould, Joseph E., 1913
      - Gowland, C. H., 1930
      - Gratacap, L. P., 1898
      - Griepentrog, Elmer L., 1936
      - Grimes, S. A., 1936
      - Grinnell, Joseph, [1911]-1939
      - Gross, Alfred O., 1945
    - Haa-Hal (Box 21, Folder 4)
      - Hagenbeck, Carl, n.d.
      - Hall, E. Raymond, 1946-1962
    - Ham-Hat (Box 21, Folder 5)
      - Hamilton, W. J. Jr., 1941
      - Hamlin, Fred, 1894-1896
      - Handley, Charles O., 1920-1946, n.d.
      - Hanna, A. J., 1927
      - Hanna, W. C., 1926
      - Hargrave, Lyndon L., n.d.
      - Hastings, Walter E., n.d.
    - Hau-Haz (Box 21, Folder 6)
      - Haupt, Herman Jr., 1890-1918
        ["Notes & Memoranda Relating to Natural Science in General as Observed and Collected"]
    - Hb-Hz (Box 21, Folder 7)
      - Helme, A. H., n.d.
      - Henderson, A. D., n.d.
      - Henderson, John B., 1922
      - Henderson, W. W., 1943
      - Hicks, John R., 1951
      - Hight, Gordon, 1953
      - Howell, Thomas R., 1959
      - Hoyt, W. D., 1923
      - Humes, Arthur G., 1938
    - J-K (Box 21, Folder 8)
      - Jackson, Ralph W., 1913
      - Jackson, Thomas H., 1911-1922, n.d.
      - Jenney, Charles F., 1909
      - Jewett, Stanley G., 1916-1935
      - Johnson, J. M., 1933
      - Jopson, J. M., 1933
      - Kellogg, Remington, 1962
      - Kent, M. H., 1917
      - Kenworthy, Ed, 1923
      - Koiner, G. W., 1913
      - Kortright, F. H., n.d.
    - L (Box 21, Folder 9)
      - Larang, John, 1918
      - Laurent, Philip, 1914
      - Law, John Eugene, 1932, n.d.
      - Lawson, Ralph, 1925
      - Lewis, Ivey F., 1947-1953
      - Ligon, J. Stokley, 1947
      - Lincoln, Frederick C., 1945-1947
      - Linton, C. B., 1906-1908
      - Litsey, John B. Jr., 1911
      - Lloyd, C. G., 1899-1906
    - Ma-Mh (Box 21, Folder 10)
      - MacGillivray, William, 1900-1905
      - Malcolm, Arthur, 1916
      - Martin del Campo, Rafael, 1937
      - Maynard, C. J., 1926
      - McKinley, Daniel, 1962
      - Merriam, Clinton Hart, 1943
    - Mi-Mn (Box 22, Folder 1)
      - Michener, Josephine R., 1971
      - Miller, Alden H., 1940
      - Miller, Frederic W., 1941
      - Miller, Gerrit S. Jr., 1937
      - Miller, Lyle DeVerne, 1949
      - Miller, Loye Holmes, 1916-1969, n.d.
      - Mitchell, H. H., 1917
    - Mo-Mz (Box 22, Folder 2)
      - Moon, Carl, 1947-1948, n.d.
        [see also Oversize Materials]
      - Moore, Joseph C., 1950-1952
      - More, Robert Lee, 1918-1941, n.d.
      - Morrison, Daniel, 1913-1924
      - Mousley, H., 1914
      - Munroe, Kirk (Mrs.), 1921
      - Murphy, Robert Cushman, 1955
      - Murray, J. J., 1936-1953
    - N-O (Box 22, Folder 3)
      - Newcombe, Curtis L., 1946
      - Norton, Arthur H., 1937
      - Oberholser, Harry C., 1926-1946
      - Orr, Robert J., 1947
      - Osgood, W. H., 1936
    - Pa-Pd (Box 22, Folder 4)
      - Pack, Arthur N., 1935
      - Palmer, T. S., 1908-1913
      - Parr, Albert Eide, 1943-[1944]
      - Paschall, Alfred, n.d.
      - Patton, John S., 1920
    - Pe-Pre (Box 22, Folder 5)
      - Peabody, P. B., n.d.
      - Pearson, T. Gilbert, 1925
      - Pember, Karl A., 1925
      - Peters, James L., 1936-1941
      - Peyton, Laurence, 1916-1917
      - Peyton, Sidney B., 1917, n.d.
      - Pierce, Wright M., n.d.
      - Pitts, John R., 1931
      - Poole, Earl L., 1933-1951, [see also Oversize Materials]
      - Pough, Richard H., 1958
      - Prather, John M., 1936
      - Preble, Edward A., 1916
    - Prf-Pz (Box 22, Folder 6)
      - Price, W. W., 1893, [collection notebooks]
    - R (Box 22, Folder 7)
      - Raine, Walter, n.d.
      - Ravenel, W. DeC., 1920
      - Rich, Guy C., 1917
      - Ritchie, Sanford, 1928
      - Rives, William C., 1913
      - Rook, Warren, 1961
      - Ryman, J. J., 1903, n.d.
      - Preble, Edward A., 1916
    - Sa-Smithv (Box 22, Folder 8)
      - Schaldach, Bill, 1961
      - Schwarz, Ernst, 1945-1947
      - Scott, Peter, 1955
      - Semple, John B., 1930, n.d.
      - Sharp, C. S., 1913-1924
      - Simpson, Charles Torrey, 1922-1933, n.d.
      - Smith, Austin Paul, 1919
    - Smithwick, R. Pearce
      - Nest and egg record (North Carolina and Virginia), 1894-1904 (Box 22, Folder 9)
      - Nest notes (North Carolina and Virginia), 1894-1909 (Box 22, Folder 10)
    - Smj-Ss (Box 23, Folder 1)
      - Snyder, L. L., 1940
      - Spicer-Simson, Theodore, 1930-1952, n.d.
      - Squires, Karl, 1930, n.d.
    - Sta-Std (Box 23, Folder 2)
      - Stanley, James E., n.d.
      - Stansell, Sidney S. S., 1909
    - Ste-Sz (Box 23, Folder 3)
      - Stephan, Joseph A., 1936
      - Stoddard, Herbert L., 1943
      - Stone, C. F., 1908-1915, n.d.
      - Sutton, George M., 1925-1943, [see also Oversize Materials]
      - Swanson, Gustave, 1938
    - Ta-Tov (Box 23, Folder 4)
      - Taverner, P. A., 1939-1946
      - Thayer, John E., 1917
      - Todd, W. E. Clyde, 1957
      - Todd, William, 1915-1917
      - Torre y Huerta, Carlos de la, [1950]
    - Tow-Toz (Box 23, Folder 5)
      - Townsend, Charles H., 1889-1944, n.d., [2 folders] (Box 23, Folder 5)
        [photographs and research materials relating to Easter Island]
    - Tp-V (Box 23, Folder 6)
      - Tufts, R. W., 1936
      - Tyler, John G., 1917
      - Van Hyning, T., 1924-1940
      - Van Tyne, J., 1939-1954
      - Vorhies, Charles T., 1945-1947
    - Wa-Wd (Box 23, Folder 7)
      - Walker, Alexander, 1911-1913
      - Warren, E. R., n.d.
    - We-Z (Box 23, Folder 8)
      - Webb, Walter F., 1935
      - Wells, Gurnie, 1914-1930, n.d.
      - Wetmore, Alexander, 1945
      - Wheaton, A. W., 1913
      - Whitaker, Lovie M., 1957
      - Whitman, Frank Nunn, n.d.
      - Whitney, Harry Payne, n.d.
      - Willett, G., 1917
      - Wilson, Alexander, 1956
      - Wilson, Gaines, n.d.
      - Wolfe, L. R., 1932, n.d.
      - Wood, J. Claire, [1905]
      - Wood, Norman A., n.d.
      - Zahniser, Howard, 1952
      - Zuercher, C. F., 1936, n.d.
    - Egg checklists, 1866-1889, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 9)
      [bound collection of individual checklists]
      - American Museum of Natural History (Bailey Collection), 1887
      - Brewster, William, 1887
      - Carpenter, F. H., 1886-1886, [2 items]
      - Clark, John N., 1886-1888, [3 items]
      - Davis, E. C., 1886
      - Dille, Fred M., n.d.
      - Doe, Chas. E., 1886
      - Emerson, W. Otto, n.d.
      - Evermann, B. W., 1886
      - Flint, W. W., 1888
      - Goodwin, F. M., 1886
      - Goss, B. F., 1886
      - Hoopes, Josiah, 1886-1889, [3 items]
      - Ingersoll, Albert M., 1886
      - Jackson, Thomas H., 1886-1888, [3 items]
      - Jones, C. M., 1886
      - Kells, William L., 1886
      - Ladd, Samuel B., 1886-1887, [2 items]
      - Lantz, D. E., 1885
      - Mitchell, R. M., 1887
      - Noble, G., 1887-1888, [2 items]
      - Norris, J. P., 1866
      - Parker, Harry G., 1886-1889, [4 items]
      - Perry, T. D., 1886
      - Preston, J. W., 1886
      - Poling, Otho C., 1887
      - Ralph, William L. and Bagg, Egbert, 1887
      - Ricksecker, Edmund, 1886, [2 items]
      - Singley, J. A., n.d.
      - Smith, Philo W. Jr., 1885
      - Stebbins, Edward S., 1886
      - Stoate, W., 1886
- SERIES IV. PRINTED MATERIALS, 1882-1969
  - Birds, 1932-1969, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 10-11)
  - Cooper Ornithological Club / Cooper Ornithological Society, 1897-1966 (Box 23, Folder 12)
  - Museums and zoos, 1922-1961, n.d. (Box 24, Folder 1-2)
  - Supply catalogs, 1882-[1911], n.d. (Box 24, Folder 3)
  - Virginia tourist attractions, 1946-1961, n.d. (Box 24, Folder 4)
  - General printed materials, 1932-1962, n .d. (Box 24, Folder 5)
    - Rossi, Edmund A., "What Is Wine?", 1932
    - Canadian Nature, Mar-Apr 1945
    - Mollusca, Apr 10 1945
    - Malacologia, Sep 1962
    - "A Tonic for Your Heart", n.d.
    - "Wildlife of Florida", n.d.
- SERIES V. IMAGES, 1904-1942
  - Subseries A. Color Plates and Other Illustrations, 1913-1922
    - Audubon Society color plates by Allan Brooks, Bruce Horsfall, Edmund J. Sawyer, Louis Agassiz Fuertes and unidentified others, n.d. (Box 25, Folder 1)
    - Color plates of North American birds and mammals by Louis Agassiz Fuertes, J. L. Ridgway, Oliver Kemp, and Sherman Foote Denton, n.d. (Box 25, Folder 2)
      [identified by Bailey as being from reports of the New York Fish Commission]
    - Color plates from The Birds of Florida by George M. Sutton, n.d. (Box 25, Folder 3-7)
    - Color plates of North American Birds by R. Ridgway and J. L. Ridgway, n.d. (Box 25, Folder 8)
    - Audubon Society's "Pictures of Alaskan Birds" by Allan Brooks, n.d. (Box 25, Folder 9)
    - Individual plates and other illustrations from various sources, 1913-1922, n.d., [40 items] (Box 25, Folder 10)
  - Subseries B. Photographs, 1902-1937
    - The Birds of Virginia
      - Original mounted photographs, n.d., [3 folders] (Box 25, Folder 11)
      - Copper engraving plates, n.d., 4 boxes; [4 boxes] (Box 25A-D)
      - Half-tone photos used by engravers, n.d., [107 items; 3 folders] (Box 26, Folder 1)
    - Hand-tinted set of nest and egg photographs, n.d.
      - Species A-B (Box 26, Folder 2)
        Missing Title
        Baltimore oriole [accompanied by black-and-white original]
        Blackbird
        Black-crowned night heron
        Blue Jay
        Bluebird [2 items]
        Bobolink [accompanied by black-and-white original]
        Brown thrasher [accompanied by black-and-white original]
      - Species C-J (Box 26, Folder 3)
        Catbird [accompanied by black-and-white original]
        Chimney swift [accompanied by black-and-white original
        Chipping sparrow
        Crow
        Field sparrow
        Indigo bunting [accompanied by black-and-white original]
      - Species K-N (Box 26, Folder 4)
        Kingbird [accompanied by black-and-white original]
        Kingfisher [accompanied by black-and-white original]
        Least bittern
        Louisiana water thrush [accompanied by black-and-white original
        Meadowlark [accompanied by black-and-white original]
      - Species O-V (Box 26, Folder 5)
        Orchard oriole [accompanied by black-and-white original]
        Ovenbird
        Pewee [accompanied by black-and-white original]
        Red-eyed vireo [accompanied by black-and-white original]
        Robin
      - Species W-Z (Box 26, Folder 6)
        Whip-poor-will [accompanied by black-and-white original]
        White-eyed vireo [accompanied by black-and-white original]
        Woodcock [accompanied by black-and-white original
        Yellow-billed cuckoo
        Yellow-breasted chat [accompanied by black-and-white original
    - Individual eggs and nests
      - Species A-Bk (Box 26, Folder 7)
        Alder flaycatcher n.d.
        American coot n.d. [2 items]